(飛段)チッ… ゼツかよ。
Zetsu, huh?
(ゼツ黒)どうやら
済んだようだな。
It appears it's done.
Finally finished with
your drawn-out ritual, huh?
(ゼツ黒)長ったらしい儀式も
終わったか。
あぁ どいつもコイツも
うるせえ野郎だ！
Nothing but annoying atheist jerks
who don't understand prayer!
祈りを知らねえ無神論者どもが！
When you're sad and alone,
you can only trust in yourself.
(ゼツ白)悲しいときは 身ひとつ。
(ゼツ黒)信じられるのは 己だけだ。
(角都)いや 違うな。
No, you're wrong.
You can only trust in money.
信じられるのは カネだけだ。
(飛段)あぁ 出た それ！
Oh, here we go!
お前の バイトのせいで➡
We've fallen behind with
our Jinchuriki hunt
人柱力探しが遅れてんだぜ。
だいたいよ…。
mostly because of your side job!
宗教は カネになると言ってきたから
お前と組んだんだ。
I teamed up with you because
you said religion is profitable.
I've been left in charge
of Akatsuki finances.
暁の財布役を任されている
オレの身にもなれ。
Put yourself in my shoes.
Money is important.
(ゼツ白)お金は大切だよね。
More importantly,
search for the next one immediately.
(ゼツ黒)そんなことより
すぐに 次を探索しろ。
二尾は オレが預かる。
I'll take charge of the Two-Tails.
Are you sure you're okay?
(ヤマト)大丈夫なのかい？
昨日まで入院していたんだろ？
You were in the hospital until
only yesterday, right?
That was just blown
out of proportion!
(ナルト)あんなの
大げさにしすぎなんだって。
(カカシ)おしゃべりは
そのくらいにして➡
That's enough talking.
Let's continue the training...
修業の続き… と
言いたいところだけど➡
That's what I'd like to say.
But first let's confirm the basics.
まず 基本の確認をしておこうか。
Forget about that!
そんなのいいってばよ！
Let's hurry up and start the training
for my new knockout Jutsu!
早く オレに 新必殺技の
修業をつけてくれよ！
The Super Ultra Deluxe Rasengan,
or the Special Uzumaki Naruto Rasengan,
超スーパーデラックス螺旋丸とか➡
ナルトスペシャル
うずまき螺旋丸とかさ！
or something like that!
(ヤマト)ハァ…。
That's what we're doing Change
in Chakra Nature training for, right?
だから そのための
チャクラの性質変化の修業でしょ。
The five basic property types are fire,
wind, water, lightning and earth.
火 風 水… 雷 土の
５種類の基本性質。
And in your case...
キミの場合は…。
オレは 風のチャクラ性質だ！
My Chakra property is wind!
じゃあ とりあえず 前に
やったとこまで やってみようか。
Then for the time being,
shall we go with what
we've done so far?
Right! Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
おう！ 多重影分身の術！
は～っ！
薄く 鋭くだってばよ！
Steady and sharp!
あぁ～！
We did it!
できた！
ど～んなもんだってばよ！
カカシ先生！
How about that, Kakashi-sensei?!
あ… あれ？
Huh?
(カカシ)まったく…。
Good grief.
病み上がりだってのに
ムチャしやがって。
He pushes it even though
he's still healing...
The Multi Shadow Clone is primarily used
そもそも 多重影分身は
修業の効率を上げるための方法。
as an approach for increasing
the effects of the training.
(ヤマト)修業の成果を見せるのには
必要ないでしょうに…。
It's not necessary for showing
the results of training.
(カカシ)ま ナルトらしいけどね。
Well, it is Naruto's style, though.
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Akatsuki's Invasion
How deep into the mountains is it?
どんだけ山奥にあるんだよ…。
もうすぐだ。
We're almost there.
って ずっと そればっかじゃん。
You've been saying that
the whole time!
Come on. Give me a break!
We've got to climb again?!
(飛段)おいおい 勘弁しろよ。
また のぼりか？
What if it turns out
there's no Jinchuriki?!
これで 人柱力がいない
ってことになってみろよ。
I'll be really upset!
オレは キレるぜ！
I don't give a damn about you.
If you keep wailing like a little kid...
(角都)お前のことなど
知ったことか。
ガキみたいに
わめいていると… 殺すぞ。
I'll kill you.
Come on.
Don't give me that, Kakuzu!
だからよ
それを オレに言うかよ 角都。
Oh, man!
What an anti-social jerk.
(飛段)あぁ 無愛想な野郎だぜ。
Even if there are several changes...
(綱手)いくつかの
変更点はあるとしても➡
this would be the best plan
under the present conditions, huh?
現状で考えられる 最良の構成か。
(シズネ)はい。
Yes.
(綱手)２～３日のうちに
まとめあげ➡
Get everything compiled and
have it ready to transmit
in two or three days.
伝達できるよう 頼む。
(シズネ)わかりました。
Understood.
Sorry to cause you trouble...
《苦労かけて すまんな。
But we can't just sit around
doing nothing.
だが ちんたらして
いられそうもないのでな…》
Are you awake?
(カカシ)目が覚めたか？
Huh...?
あれ？ オレってば また…。
Again... I...
You keep resting.
(カカシ)まだ寝てろ。
Fatigue tends to build up
多重影分身を使った修業方法は
疲れも たまりやすいからな。
when using the Multi Shadow Clones
training approach.
Let's start the training again
after you've rested a little while.
(カカシ)もう少し休んでから
修業を始めよう。
What're we going to do next?
次は 何するんだ？
Next?
次か？ 次のステップは…。
The next step is...
to cut that waterfall!
(カカシ)滝を切る。
Put your hands on the waterfall
and cut it
滝に手をつけて 風のチャクラを
思いっきりぶつけて 切るんだ。
by hammering it
with your Wind Chakra.
切るって 滝を？
Cut... the waterfall?
For this training,
you need to instantly create
瞬時に 多量の
性質変化を起こす訓練だよ。
a Change in Chakra Nature
in a large amount of Chakra.
Or else you won't be able
to cut the waterfall.
そうしないと
滝なんて切れないからね。
You'll more or less be able
to use it in real battle
(カカシ)この段階をクリアできれば➡
if you can pass this stage of training.
とりあえず 実戦で使えるからな。
Kakashi-sensei!
カカシ先生 それができりゃ➡
If I can do that,
it means I have learned
my first Change in Chakra Nature, right?
オレもまず 一つの性質変化は
できたってことか？
All right, I'm getting better!
ようし オレ 成長してるってばよ！
I never thought that clumsy Naruto
《カカシ : あの不器用なナルトが➡
would be able to create
a Change in Chakra Nature so soon.
ここまで早く 性質変化を
起こせるようになるとは➡
思ってもみなかった。
This training approach...
was a big success.
この修業方法 大正解だったな》
Break time is over!
休憩終わり！
Let's get right back to training!
さっさと 修業再開だってばよ！
Wood Style Jutsu!
(ヤマト)木遁の術！
That will be your training area.
(カカシ)あそこが今度の 修業場だ。
Right.
うん！
(カカシ)でも ちょい待ち。
But hold on!
Whoa... What is it?
なんだってばよ!?
この修業は常に➡
You'll need Yamato's Chakra control
at all times during this training.
ヤマトの チャクラコントロールが必要だって
言ってるでしょ。
I'm counting on you, Yamato.
頼んだよ ヤマト。
はい。
Okay.
(ヤマト)ハッ！
Preparations complete, Naruto!
準備完了だよ ナルト。
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
多重影分身の術！
Form a mental image
of my Wind Chakra and...
《風のチャクラをイメージして…》
Listen up. The Wind Change
in Chakra Nature...
((アスマ : いいか？ 風の性質変化は
チャクラを２つに分割して➡
splits Chakra in two and
grinds them together.
すり合わせるイメージだ。
すり合わせる？
Grinds them together?
And then you build up the two Chakra
as if steadily sharpening them.
そして ２つのチャクラを 互いに
薄く研ぐような感じで練り込め。
As if steadily... sharpening them...
薄く 鋭く… 研ぐような感じか。
That's right...
The trick is steadier... and sharper.
(そうだ コツは より薄く 鋭くだ))
Steady and sharp!
薄く… 鋭くだ！
Let's go, guys!
みんな いくぞ！
おぉ！
Right!
ハッ！
Damn it! The water should
splash just a bit...
クッソ～！ 水が ちょいハネる程度か。
Let's go to the next one!
次いくぞ！ 次！
おうよ！
Right!
ハッ！
As to be expected,
this will probably take a while.
(ヤマト)これは さすがに
時間が かかりそうですね。
Well, be patient.
まっ 気長にね。
ハッ！ ハッ！
That should be it for the ingredients...
(サクラ)材料は これでよしっと。
Now I can make him some of
my special Sakura Food Pills!
これで サクラ特製 スペシャル兵糧丸を
作ってあげられる。
I'm sure he'll force himself
into doing more reckless training.
《サクラ : アイツ きっとムリして➡
ムチャな修業するに
違いないんだから》
Geez...
《ったく 今どき流行らないわよ
根性で強くなるなんて。
Getting stronger with determination
just isn't done anymore.
Not only does excessive training
take a toll on the body,
ムリな修業は 体に負担を
かけるだけじゃなくて➡
but it could also have
a reverse effect.
逆効果になることだってある。
ましてや アイツは 人一倍
がんばることができる 特異体質》
Not only that, he also has
the physical idiosyncrasy
that allows him to work much harder
than other people.
That's right! The least I can do
is to help him any way I can.
《サクラ : そうよ せめて
私のできることで➡
力になってあげなきゃ》
ハッ！ ハッ！ ハッ！
ハァ～！ ハッ！
Damn it!
チクショウ！ クッソ～！
Damn...
ハッ！ ハッ！ ハッ！
He'll probably start getting
impatient pretty soon.
そろそろ じれ出す頃かな。
This is a temple.
Is there a Jinchuriki in a place like this?
(飛段)寺じゃねえかよ。
こんなところにいんのかよ？
Who knows?
(角都)さあな。 だが
ただの寺ではないからな➡
But this isn't an ordinary temple,
so there's a good possibility.
可能性は高い。
What was that?!
何事だ!?
封印鉄壁を 破った者がおる！
Someone destroyed the Iron Wall Seal!
Report this to Chiriku-sama!
地陸様に報告しろ！
(飛段)ジャシン教には➡
It doesn't look like these guys
want to convert to the Jashin religion.
改宗してくれそうにねえ
ツラしてんな どいつもコイツも。
None of these guys do...
あの衣… 今ウワサの！
That cloak... It's the rumored...
No doubt about it! It's the Akatsuki!
間違いない 暁だ！
We have intruders!
侵入者です！
(地陸)何者だ？
Who are they?
They are with the Akatsuki!
暁の手の者でございます！
《地陸 : いつか来るとは
思っていたが…》
I knew they'd come here eventually, but...
I'll go!
Everyone else provide backup.
わしが出る。
他の者は 援護しろ。
(飛段)あ？ また徳の高そうなのが
出てきたぜ。
Looks like we've got another
virtuous looking one...
He's not just virtuous.
(角都)徳だけではない。
He's got a 30 million ryo bounty
on his head in our Bingo Book.
こちら側のビンゴブックでは
3,000万両の賞金首だ。
(飛段)ハッ… おい 金儲けが
狙いじゃねえだろうな？
Hey...
You're not after money, are you?
You'll go to hell if you kill
a monk for something like that.
そんなんで坊主やると
地獄へ落ちるぜ。
Money is the key that opens all doors.
That's just what I want.
地獄の沙汰も カネ次第だ。
望むところ。
I don't know what you guys want.
But please leave quietly.
(地陸)貴殿ら 何用かは知らぬが
おとなしく帰られよ。
No meaningless slaughter, huh?
無益な殺生は しねえってか？
But it doesn't work like that
in my religion.
だが こっちの宗派じゃ
そうはいかねえ。
火ノ国に火ノ寺ありと
謳われた忍寺だ。
The Temple of Fire is the greatest
Shinobi temple in the Land of Fire.
And it is said that all of the monks
control the special power
僧侶は みな
仙族の才と呼ばれる特別な力を➡
known as the Gift of the Sages.
操ると言われている。
And the 30 million-ryo man is a Ninja
(角都)特に あの 3,000万両は➡
who was once chosen as a member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve
火ノ国の大名を守る
守護忍十二士にも➡
who protected the Feudal Lord
of the Land of Fire.
選ばれたこともある エリート忍者だ。
And the proof is that breechcloth
with the Land of Fire emblem on it...
あの火ノ国の紋が入った
腰布が その証し。
へぇ それって すげえの？
No kidding?
Is he that incredible?
Don't get careless.
You'll die.
(角都)気を抜くな… 死ぬぞ。
Don't give me that...
だから オレに それを言うかよ！
(飛段)角都！
Kakuzu!
何だ あれは!?
What's that?!
I don't care.
Let's keep going.
かまわねえ このまま突っ込むぜ。
(飛段)もらった！
You're mine!
- Oh.
- Chiriku-sama won!
葬儀は出してやる。
I'll give you a funeral.
(飛段)誰が…
異教の葬儀なんか受けるかよ。
Who would accept
a different religion's funeral?
ジャシン様のバチが当たるぜ。
I'd receive divine retribution
from Lord Jashin...
頭きた… おい
コイツは人柱力じゃねえんだろ。
Now I'm mad...
Hey...
If this guy isn't a Jinchuriki...
I can defend my commandments, right?
なら オレの戒律
守っていいんだよな。
(角都)好きにしろ。
だが コイツの死体は カネになる。
Do as you like.
But his body is worth money.
Don't go overboard...
Make sure he's recognizable.
(角都)誰だか わかるように
ほどほどにしとけよ。
命を カネに換えるなんざ➡
Exchanging life for money
isn't something for people to do...
人のやることじゃねえぜ
…ったくよ！
Good grief.
Kakuzu! Stay out of this!
(飛段)角都 手を出すなよ！
I'll take care of... this guy!
コイツは オレが… やる！
火ノ寺の地陸。
Chiriku of the Temple of Fire will
not lose to wicked men like you!
キサマらごとき外道には
負けはせん！
Raikei!
来迎 千手殺！
Thousand Hand Strike!
(飛段)ぐぉ～!!
どうやら ここには
人柱力は いなかったみてえだな。
It appears there was no Jinchuriki here.
祈りが終わりしだい
次へ行こうぜ。
Let's move on to the next one as soon
as I'm done with my prayer.
No...
(角都)イヤ…
コイツの死体を換金所に持って行く。
I'm taking this body to trade in for money.
Money comes first.
まずは金だ。
あのさ！ オレ お前に１回
キレてもいいかな!? ホント！
Listen, you're really starting
to irritate me. Really...
《木ノ葉へ知らせなければ！》
I've got to inform the Hidden Leaf...
(飛段)だったら
とっとと行こうぜ。
Then let's get going.
The Land of Fire is huge.
Let's take our time.
火ノ国は広い… じっくり行くぞ。
やっぱ いろいろと出遅れてんのは
テメエのせいだろ！ クーッ いてえ！
I knew we were falling behind
because of you.
Ow!
待てや！ こら!!
Wait! Hey!
カカシ先生！
Kakashi-sensei!
これじゃ 影分身が
少なすぎるんじゃねえの!?
Don't you think I need
more Shadow Clones?!
(カカシ)大量のチャクラを風に
性質変化させなきゃ滝は切れない。
You can't cut the waterfall
unless you perform
the Change in Chakra Nature
on a large amount of wind Chakra!
The Chakra for each clone will disperse
if there are too many of them!
人数が多すぎれば 一人ひとりの
チャクラが分散しちまう。
And we can barely line up ten clones
with the width of that waterfall!
それに その滝の幅じゃ
10人並ぶのが やっとだ。
Do you really want me
to learn this or not
え～！ なんだよそれ…。
Then tell us the trick to get just
a little bit better!
だったら
ちょっとぐらい うまくなるコツ➡
教えてくれってばよ！
(カカシ)作ったチャクラを
体内に溜める時間が短すぎる。
You're not holding the Chakra
you've built up inside
your body long enough!
もっと時間をかけて丁寧にやれ。
Take your time and be more efficient!
でも チンタラやってたら
実戦で役に立たねえじゃん！
But if we don't get a move on,
this won't be of any use in a real battle.
今は修業中だ。
実戦のことまで考えなくていい。
You're in training right now.
You don't need to be thinking
about real battles.
慣れれば早くなる。
でも…！
It will get quicker
once you get used to it.
But...
あのね… 性質変化は
本来 何年もかかる修業なの。
Listen...
Change in Chakra Nature training
normally takes several years.
葉を切るのだって
ホントなら半年はかかる。
Under normal conditions,
it takes six months to even cut a leaf.
(ヤマト)それを たった数時間で
クリアしたんだ。 焦ることないよ。
You completed that in only
a few hours.
No need to be so impatient.
予想より何倍も早く進んでる。
You're progressing several times
faster than we expected.
(カカシ)天才肌のサスケでさえ
千鳥を教えたとき➡
It even took a genius like Sasuke
several days
to master the Lightning Change
in Chakra Nature
雷の性質変化には
かなりの日数がかかった。
when I taught him the Chidori.
オレは そのサスケに
追いつかなきゃなんねえんだ！
I have to catch up with Sasuke!
(カカシ)…ったく。
Good grief...
(カカシ)テンゾウ。
Tenzo...
わかりました。
Understood.
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
さすがに きついか？
That was a little tough on you, huh?
No! Not at all.
まったく…。
全然…。
N-Not in the least...
《きついんだな…》
It was tough...
(カカシ)どうだ ナルト？
これで文句ないだろ？
How's that, Naruto?!
Now you've got nothing
to gripe about, right?!
ヘヘヘヘ… 多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ハッ！
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
よい子のみんな 元気かな？
今日 みんなと一緒に挑戦するのは
この術！
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
火遁豪火球の術だ。
(子供たち)火遁豪火球？
(カカシ)そう！ 火遁豪火球とは
うちは一族に伝わる基本忍術。
Next Episode
Wh-What did you say?
The Temple of Fire was attacked?!
体内で練ったチャクラを炎に変えて
火の球を口から吐き出す➡
It was probably guys from
the Akatsuki.
サスケの得意技だ。
They're going one by one
to locations in the Land of Fire
発動のために必要な印は
次の６つ。
where there might be Jinchuriki.
They've come at last.
We won't let them out of
the Land of Fire.
Contact the twenty newly
formed platoons immediately!
(カカシ)午の印はちょっと難しいから
練習が必要かな。
Yes, ma'am!
I want to know what they're after,
but they are pretty powerful.
すばやく印を結びながら
体内で チャクラを練り上げて➡
Destroy them
if they can't be restrained!
ノドのあたりに一度 溜めてから
一気に吐き出す！
Next time: "Under the Starry Sky"
それじゃあ
みんなで やってみよう！
Under the Starry Sky
— Let's all try it together!
(カカシ)チャクラを練ったら溜めて～
一気に吐く！
How are you kids doing?
The jutsu we're going to
take a crack at today is
あのサスケだって はじめから
うまくできたわけじゃない！
the Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
- Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu?
何事も修業あるのみ！
それじゃあ またね！ バイバーイ！
That's right.
The Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu is
a basic ninjutsu passed down
through the Uchiha Clan.
You convert the chakra you've
built up in your body into flames
and shoot out fire balls
from your mouth.
It's Sasuke's specialty.
The following six seals are necessary
to activate the jutsu.
Snake, Sheep, Monkey,
Boar, Ox and Tiger.
The Ox seal is a bit difficult,
$0 you may need practice.
While creating the seals
in quick succession
you build up chakra in your body
and then draw it up to your throat
and spit it out all at once.
Now, let's all try it together!
Snake, Sheep, Monkey,
Boar, Ox, Tiger.
Build up the chakra and then
spit it out all at once!
Even Sasuke couldn't do it very well
at the start.
Practice makes perfect!
See you guys later.
Bye-bye!